colostate.edu 2009-12-19

# Privacy Policy of Colorado State University - Fort Collins

## Commitment to Individual Privacy

Colorado State University is committed to protecting the privacy and accuracy of confidential information submitted by employees, students, and visitors to our Web site. We do not actively share personal information gathered. However, because Colorado State University is a public institution, some information collected from the Colorado State University Web site may be subject to the Colorado Public (Open) Records Act. Thus, in some cases we may be compelled by law to release information gathered from our Web servers. This may include server log information, e-mail messages sent to an individual identified on the Web site, and information collected from Web-based forms.

## Colorado Public (Open) Records Act (C.R.S. 24-72 201 _et seq_.)

It is the declared public policy of the State of Colorado that all public records shall be open for inspection by any person at reasonable times, except as otherwise provided by law. Public Records are defined by this law as all writings made or maintained by a state institution, such as Colorado State University, regardless of the format or medium of the records.

## Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (20 U.S.C. §1232g)

Colorado State University also complies with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which generally prohibits the release of students' education records without consent. FERPA only applies to currently enrolled students. For more information on FERPA please refer to the Student Rights and Responsibilities Section of the Colorado State University General Catalog.

## Information Collection

It is Colorado State University's policy to collect the least amount of personally identifiable information required to fulfill its required duties and responsibilities, to complete a particular transaction or as required by law. This policy applies to the collection of all personally identifiable information, regardless of the source or medium.

For site administration functions, information, other than personal information linked to a particular individual, is collected for analysis and statistical purposes of Web site navigation. This information is used to help diagnose problems, assess what information is of most interest, determine technical design specifications, identify system performance and/or problem areas, and other administration functions.

You may choose whether or not to provide personal information to Colorado State University via the Internet. If you choose not to provide the personal information we request, you can still visit most of Colorado State University's Web sites, but you may be unable to access certain options, offers, and services that involve our interaction with you.

## Security

Wherever your personal information may be held within Colorado State University or on its behalf, we intend to take reasonable and appropriate steps to protect the information that you share with us from unauthorized access or disclosure.

## Browser Cookies

Some of our Web pages utilize "cookies." A "cookie" is a small text file that may be used, for example, to collect information about Web site activity. Some cookies may serve to recall personal information previously indicated by a Web user. Cookies created by Colorado State University Web pages cannot be read by a third party. Most browsers allow you to control cookies, including whether or not to accept them and how to remove them. You may set most browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie, or you may choose to block cookies with your browser.

## Tracking Technologies

Tracking technologies may record information such as Internet domain and host names; Internet protocol (IP) addresses; browser software and operating system types; clock stream patterns; and dates and times that our site is accessed. Our use of tracking technologies allows us to analyze trends and statistics to improve our Web site and your Web experience. Data used from tracking technologies is not linked to Web users' personal information.

## Third Party Services

On Colorado State University's behalf, third parties may provide certain services available on Colorado State University Web sites. Colorado State University may provide information, including personal information, collected on the Web to third-party service providers to help us deliver programs, products, information and services. Service providers are also an important means by which Colorado State University maintains its Web site and mailing lists. We will take reasonable steps to ensure that these third-party service providers are obligated to protect personal information on our behalf.

## Disclaimer

The information provided in this privacy statement should NOT be construed as giving business, legal, or other advice, or as warranting the security of information provided through this Web site.
